<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Virtualbox on Victor&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.victormendonca.com/tags/virtualbox/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Virtualbox on Victor&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>(c) 2018 Copyright Victor Mendonça</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 13:45:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.victormendonca.com/tags/virtualbox/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Change macOS Key Bindings</title>
      <link>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2020/04/27/how-to-change-macos-key-bindings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 13:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2020/04/27/how-to-change-macos-key-bindings/</guid>
      <description>This post will show you how to change line movement and control key bindings in macOS to be similar to what we use in Linux (and windows).
The following keyboard shortcuts will be added:
   Sequence Command     Ctrl+Left Back one word   Ctrl+Right Forward one word   Ctrl+Shift+Left Back one word and modify selection   Ctrl+Shift+Right Forward one word and modify selection   Home Beginning of the line   End End of line   Shift+Home Beginning of the line and modify selection   Shift+End End of line and modify selection   Ctrl+Home Top of page   Ctrl+End End of page   Shift+Ctrl+Home Top of page and modify selection   Shift+Ctrl+End End of page and modify selection    Instructions a.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Install macOS Catalina in Virtual Box</title>
      <link>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2020/04/17/how-to-install-macos-catalina-in-virtual-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 22:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2020/04/17/how-to-install-macos-catalina-in-virtual-box/</guid>
      <description>This document will provide instructions on getting a macOS Catalina install working with Guest Additions on VirtaulBox 6.1.
Start by downloading a copy of the installer from the App Store. You will need a computer running macOS and you will need to convert the installer to an ISO. I will not be covering these steps here, but there are plenty tutorials online.
Installing VirtualBox I&amp;rsquo;m hoping you already have this part covered and you are coming here only because you had issues getting macOS installed, but just in case, make sure the following packages are installed (Arch):</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>