<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Storage on Victor&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.victormendonca.com/tags/storage/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Storage on Victor&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>(c) 2018 Copyright Victor Mendonça</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 14:21:40 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.victormendonca.com/tags/storage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing New Hard Drives</title>
      <link>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2023/11/21/testing-new-hard-drives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 14:21:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2023/11/21/testing-new-hard-drives/</guid>
      <description>So you got a spanking new hard drive for your NAS and you are ready to install it&amp;hellip; but wait! What if the drive is bad?
This is not something that most people would think of, but that shiny new drive could already have come with defects (a.k.a extra features) from the factory. Or maybe it was part of a fun game of &amp;ldquo;throw the client&amp;rsquo;s package&amp;rdquo; that some delivery man like to play (as my preferred social media likes to show me).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Quickly Create an Encrypted USB Drive on KDE Plasma</title>
      <link>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2020/10/21/how-to-create-an-encrypted-usb-drive-on-kde-plasma/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 15:32:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2020/10/21/how-to-create-an-encrypted-usb-drive-on-kde-plasma/</guid>
      <description>Need to create an encrypted USB drive? Are your running KDE Plasma?
Then great! Here are 6 simple steps on how to quickly and painlessly create an encrypted USB drive with KDE Partition Manager.
Let&amp;rsquo;s start a. Start by inserting your USB drive
b. Now launch KDE Parition Manager and type your password
c. Select the USB drive and right click to delete the existing partition
 ⚠️ WARNING: remember, this will delete all your existing files)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Show Progress for dd</title>
      <link>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2020/10/09/how-to-show-progress-for-dd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 11:28:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2020/10/09/how-to-show-progress-for-dd/</guid>
      <description>If you have reached this page I expect that you already know what dd is. But you if you don&amp;rsquo;t, dd is a command-line utility that is used to convert and copy files. It&amp;rsquo;s commonly found on various (Linux) distro help pages that show new users how to setup USB (or Micro SD) drives to install or run (like Raspberry Pi) the OS.
One of the main problems is that when running the dd utility, it does not provide any information on the current status of the copy process.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>