<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hardware on Victor&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.victormendonca.com/tags/hardware/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hardware on Victor&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>(c) 2018 Copyright Victor Mendonça</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 11:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.victormendonca.com/tags/hardware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Configure a UPS Between Linux and FreeNAS</title>
      <link>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2020/10/22/how-to-configure-a-ups-between-linux-and-freenas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2020/10/22/how-to-configure-a-ups-between-linux-and-freenas/</guid>
      <description>After having bad memory modules due to power outages at home (on both my FreeNAS and my desktop) I knew I had to invest on a UPS. I will cover the details of the configuration, and as usual, I will try to go straight to the point.
Keep in mind that I&amp;rsquo;m running Arch on my desktop and FreeNAS-11.3-U1, and that the UPS is connected to my desktop (master) via USB.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Quickly Create an Encrypted USB Drive on KDE Plasma</title>
      <link>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2020/10/21/how-to-create-an-encrypted-usb-drive-on-kde-plasma/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 15:32:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2020/10/21/how-to-create-an-encrypted-usb-drive-on-kde-plasma/</guid>
      <description>Need to create an encrypted USB drive? Are your running KDE Plasma?
Then great! Here are 6 simple steps on how to quickly and painlessly create an encrypted USB drive with KDE Partition Manager.
Let&amp;rsquo;s start a. Start by inserting your USB drive
b. Now launch KDE Parition Manager and type your password
c. Select the USB drive and right click to delete the existing partition
 ⚠️ WARNING: remember, this will delete all your existing files)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Install Waveshare 3.5&#34; LCD on Ubuntu 20.04</title>
      <link>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2020/10/13/how-to-install-waveshare-3.5inch-lcd-on-ubuntu-20.04/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 14:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2020/10/13/how-to-install-waveshare-3.5inch-lcd-on-ubuntu-20.04/</guid>
      <description>Following the steps of an older post (Installing Kuman 3), I find myself trying to configure the same Waveshare 3.5&amp;raquo; LCD touch screen on my Raspberry Pi 3B, but now with Ubuntu 20.04 64.bit.
As usual the LCDs from Waveshare are not that easy to configure. While researching online I could not find any working instructions on how to configure the screen with Ubuntu 20.04. I found a few Git repos (Wavesahre and LCD Wiki), but they all failed to get me with a working config.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Show Progress for dd</title>
      <link>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2020/10/09/how-to-show-progress-for-dd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 11:28:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2020/10/09/how-to-show-progress-for-dd/</guid>
      <description>If you have reached this page I expect that you already know what dd is. But you if you don&amp;rsquo;t, dd is a command-line utility that is used to convert and copy files. It&amp;rsquo;s commonly found on various (Linux) distro help pages that show new users how to setup USB (or Micro SD) drives to install or run (like Raspberry Pi) the OS.
One of the main problems is that when running the dd utility, it does not provide any information on the current status of the copy process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TLP and CPUFreq on ThinkPad P1 Gen 2 (KDE Arch)</title>
      <link>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2020/06/17/lenovo-p1-gen-tlp-on-arch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 20:00:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2020/06/17/lenovo-p1-gen-tlp-on-arch/</guid>
      <description>On this tutorial I will show you how to install and configure TLP and Intel P-state and CPUFreq Manager on your ThinkPad P1 Gen 2 (with KDE Arch).
If you don&amp;rsquo;t know, TLP allows you to configure specific rules to help optimize the battery life on your laptop, while Intel P-state and CPUFreq Manager gives you a pretty interface via a tray icon that allows you to control CPU/GPU frequencies and a few power profiles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Touchpad Gestures on XPS 13</title>
      <link>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2019/04/15/touchpad-gestures-on-xps-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 18:14:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2019/04/15/touchpad-gestures-on-xps-13/</guid>
      <description>The XPS 13 is a great laptop and it comes with an equally matched touchpad. Setting up touch gestures is pretty easy, and we will cover what needs to be done to get it working on Arch.
First, let&amp;rsquo;s install all the needed software:
 extra/libinput aur/libinput-gestures  After installing the 2 packages you should be able to run libinput-gestures -d as root and try the pre-defined gestures. You should see an output when you swipe left/right/up/down with &amp;frac34; fingers and pinch in/out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Kuman 3</title>
      <link>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2018/06/26/installing-kuman-3.5-tft-lcd-on-raspberry-pi-3-model-b/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 18:36:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2018/06/26/installing-kuman-3.5-tft-lcd-on-raspberry-pi-3-model-b/</guid>
      <description>Simple instructions (assuming a new Raspbian install) to install Kuman 3.5 TFT LCD on Raspberry Pi 3 Model B.
a. Download Rasbian strech (with desktop) and extract the .img file from the downloaded zip (it&amp;rsquo;s always good to also check the hash of the downloaded file)
b. Insert the SD card and make note of the device being used (make sure you get this right not to overwrite your OS)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Stand-up Desk Build</title>
      <link>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2017/12/25/custom-standup-desk-build/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Dec 2017 11:09:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2017/12/25/custom-standup-desk-build/</guid>
      <description>After commuting close to 1000kms a week for 6 years, I have decided to the the leap and move to Toronto. After all, I was here around 4 nights a week, and having to commute back and forward between Mississauga and Toronto had become a hassle. This would also increase my work drive (from 85kms each way to 115kms), but luckily my client agreed for me to work remote 4 days of the week, with made my move even more possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gnome Touchpad Settings Missing in Arch Xps 13</title>
      <link>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2017/09/23/gnome-touchpad-settings-missing-in-arch-xps-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 22:47:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2017/09/23/gnome-touchpad-settings-missing-in-arch-xps-13/</guid>
      <description>I had an issue where the Gnome extension &amp;lsquo;Touchpad Indicator&amp;rsquo; stopped working on my xps 13 (Arch). After looking a bit further, it seems that the Gnome Touchpad settings had also stopped working. All I could see was the mouse settings, and the touchpad section was completelly gone.
Solution:
With Gnome 3.20, xf86-input-synaptics is not longer supported, and you should use xf86-input-libinput instead.
You can check what is installed on your Arch system with pacman -Q | grep input.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>