<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Containers on Victor&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.victormendonca.com/tags/containers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Containers on Victor&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>(c) 2018 Copyright Victor Mendonça</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 17:40:13 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.victormendonca.com/tags/containers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating OS Updates on LXD Instances with Ansible</title>
      <link>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2025/11/03/automating-os-updates-on-lxd-instances-with-ansible/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 17:40:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2025/11/03/automating-os-updates-on-lxd-instances-with-ansible/</guid>
      <description>Keeping your LXD containers and VMs up to date can be a bit of a hassle — especially when you’re managing different distributions or even Windows instances. That’s why I built lxd-os-update, an Ansible project designed to automate the process of running OS updates across all your LXD environments.
It’s a simple yet powerful playbook that takes care of the entire cycle for you:
 Starts stopped and frozen instances (configurable) Runs OS updates for both APT and YUM-based Linux distros Updates Windows servers via SSH and PowerShell Restores each instance to its previous stopped or frozen state afterward  Why I Built It When managing multiple LXD projects, I often needed a way to keep everything patched without manually starting, updating, and stopping each instance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LXD: Creating Reusable RHEL 9 VM Images</title>
      <link>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2025/09/25/lxd-creating-reusable-rhel-9-vm-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 05:00:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2025/09/25/lxd-creating-reusable-rhel-9-vm-images/</guid>
      <description>Following the LXD theme of my previous posts, today I’m going to walk you through creating a RHEL 9 VM on LXD, and then show you how to turn that VM into an image. This way, you can spin up new RHEL 9 VMs whenever you want—without having to sit through the whole install/setup process again.
To follow along, you’ll need an active Red Hat subscription. If you’re doing this for personal use (like self-development, home lab tinkering, or just because you enjoy virtual machines as much as Netflix), you can download RHEL for free when you sign up for the Red Hat Developer Subscription for Individuals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring LXD (The Linux Container Daemon)</title>
      <link>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2025/09/03/exploring-lxd-the-linux-container-daemon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 09:06:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2025/09/03/exploring-lxd-the-linux-container-daemon/</guid>
      <description>Last week, I attended a virtual talk hosted by Canonical on building a homelab with microservices. During the session, I discovered a new (to me) and very cool utility that&amp;rsquo;s perfect for managing virtual machines and containers from a centralized interface: LXD, or the Linux Container Daemon.
While LXD isn&amp;rsquo;t new—it’s actually been around since 2016—it’s still flying under the radar for a lot of homelab enthusiasts. After seeing it in action, I realized it&amp;rsquo;s a hidden gem worth exploring.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>