<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Redhat on Victor&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.victormendonca.com/tags/redhat/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Redhat on Victor&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>(c) 2018 Copyright Victor Mendonça</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 15:55:27 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.victormendonca.com/tags/redhat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>RHCSA v8: Linux Logical Volume Manager</title>
      <link>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2020/11/18/linux-logical-volume-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 15:55:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2020/11/18/linux-logical-volume-manager/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer This blog post is essentially my study notes for the RHCSA v8 exam on Logical Volume Manager. It should be taken as a quick reference document (or a cheat sheet of some sorts).
It covers the following exam subjects:
 Configure local storage  Create and remove physical volumes Assign physical volumes to volume groups Create and delete logical volumes  Create and configure file systems  Extend existing logical volumes   Note: There could be additional information needed for the exam that is not covered here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RHCSA v8: Boot Targets, Systemd Targets and root Password Reset</title>
      <link>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2020/11/14/rhcsa8-boot-targets-system-targets-and-root-password-reset/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 16:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2020/11/14/rhcsa8-boot-targets-system-targets-and-root-password-reset/</guid>
      <description>For quite a while the RHCSA exam has covered topics related to boot targets and the famous root password reset. However, with the introduction of systemd and other related changes this can sometimes become a bit confusing. The methods that were once used for RHEL 6/7 may no longer be available or may not be the &amp;lsquo;official&amp;rsquo; way of doing things anymore.
I will try to clear some of the differences so we can have a better understanding of what&amp;rsquo;s needed for the RHCSAv8 exam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RHCSA v8: Work with Package Module Streams</title>
      <link>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2020/03/15/rhcsa-v8-work-with-package-module-streams/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 20:52:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2020/03/15/rhcsa-v8-work-with-package-module-streams/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer These are my study notes for the RHCSA exam on YUM modules. There&amp;rsquo;s most likely more information than what&amp;rsquo;s needed for the exam, and I cannot guarantee that all information is correct.
Definition RHEL 8 content is distributed through two main repositories: BaseOS and AppStream.
BaseOS Content in the BaseOS repository is intended to provide the core set of the underlying OS functionality that provides the foundation for all installations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RHCSA v8: Configure Disk Compression</title>
      <link>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2020/03/14/rhsa-v8-configure-disk-compression/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 14:56:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2020/03/14/rhsa-v8-configure-disk-compression/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer These are my study notes for the RHCSA exam on disk compression. There&amp;rsquo;s most likely more information than what&amp;rsquo;s needed for the exam, and I cannot guarantee that all information is correct.
Definition Virtual Data Optimizer (VDO) provides inline data reduction for Linux in the form of deduplication, compression, and thin provisioning. When you set up a VDO volume, you specify a block device on which to construct your VDO volume and the amount of logical storage you plan to present.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RHCSA v8: What&#39;s New</title>
      <link>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2020/03/14/rhcsa---whats-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 11:31:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2020/03/14/rhcsa---whats-new/</guid>
      <description>The updated RHCSA exam for RHEL 8 has been out since last year, however, the old exam is still available, and will stay available until August 1st, 2020:
You may be trying to figure out what version will be best for you, and I&amp;rsquo;m hoping the information here will help you.
Something to take in consideration is that the exam is valid for 3 years, or 2 releases (meaning that once RHEL 9 is out, your RHSCA on RHEL 7 is no longer valid).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>