<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kde on Victor&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.victormendonca.com/tags/kde/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kde on Victor&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>(c) 2018 Copyright Victor Mendonça</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 12:10:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.victormendonca.com/tags/kde/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Latte as a Dock in Kde</title>
      <link>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2018/10/18/using-latte-as-a-dock-in-kde/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 12:10:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2018/10/18/using-latte-as-a-dock-in-kde/</guid>
      <description>Latte is a great &amp;laquo;newish&amp;raquo; dock for KDE that can be used as launching/task dock, or even completely replace your plasma panels. The dock is fast stable with a good &amp;laquo;feel&amp;raquo;, and it fully supports plasma widgets.
I myself do not like the Apple like task docks. I prefer using docks for app launching and let my panels do the task management. I was looking for a fast dock for my Arch VM at work, and Latte was one of the best options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KDE Win7 Volume Mixer</title>
      <link>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2018/08/20/kde-win7-volume-mixer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 12:54:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2018/08/20/kde-win7-volume-mixer/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s not often that we see Linux using something inspired by Microsoft, and this is one of those cases. If you are running KDE as your default DE, you should definitely take a look at &amp;laquo;Win7 Volume Mixer&amp;raquo; as an alternative to the default volume mixer. It adds a great visual and a more user friendly interface.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick visual comparison:
Default Mixer
Win7 Volume Mixer</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Fix Sddm on Multiple Screens</title>
      <link>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2018/06/29/how-to-fix-sddm-on-multiple-screens/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 19:20:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.victormendonca.com/2018/06/29/how-to-fix-sddm-on-multiple-screens/</guid>
      <description>When running multiple screens on KDE with SDDM, your configuration will not be loaded until you actually login to the KDE desktop, so you might end up having screens out of order, or enabled/disabled when they should not be. To fix this is simple, and here&amp;rsquo;s how.
Let&amp;rsquo;s get a list of the devices name, size and position with xrandr:
$ xrandr | grep &#39; connected&#39; DP-1 connected (normal left inverted right x axis y axis) DP-3 connected 1920x1080+1920+0 (normal left inverted right x axis y axis) 480mm x 270mm DP-5 connected primary 1920x1080+0+0 (normal left inverted right x axis y axis) 598mm x 337mm  As you can see, on my computer I have 3x monitors:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>